{"tossups": [{"question": "This event\u2019s fourth principle declared that \u201csuperior orders\u201d do not relieve a person from lawful responsibility. Seven subjects of these events were taken to Spandau. Their location was chosen symbolically, as it had hosted an annual propaganda rally and was the city where, in 1935, a harsh set of anti-Semitic laws was signed. Luftwaffe commander Hermann Goring was sentenced to death at, for ten points, what series of trials in which Nazi leaders were tried for war crimes?", "answer": "<b> Nuremberg</b> trials", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s autobiography details his successful separation of the conjoined twins Josef and Theresia Binder, though his scientific credentials were criticized in 2015 after he denied Big Bang theory. This author of<em> Gifted Hands</em> gave the keynote address at the 2013 National Prayer Breakfast and, in September 2015, stated that a Muslim should not be in charge of the United States. For ten points, name this Republican presidential candidate and retired neurosurgeon.", "answer": "Ben<b> Carson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This founder and editor of<em> The Crisis</em> magazine broke with an organization he co-founded over his opinion of the \u201cseparate but equal\u201d doctrine. This man\u2019s Niagara movement disagreed with Booker T. Washington\u2019s Atlanta compromise, instead holding that the small, elite \u201cTalented Tenth\u201d should seek full political authority in the South. For ten points, name this author of<em> The Souls of Black Folk</em> and co-founder of the NAACP.", "answer": "William Edward Burghardt (W.E.B.)<b> Du Bois</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This politician explained his views of federalism in his Disquisition on Government, and he described slavery as a \u201cpositive good.\u201d He succeed Abel Upshur, who was killed in the<em> USS Princeton</em> explosion, as Secretary of State under John Tyler. For ten points, name this South Carolina politician who served as Vice President for John Quincy Adams and Andrew Jackson who supported nullification.", "answer": "John C.<b> Calhoun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s head was immersed in a jar of blood by Queen Tomyris to satisfy his bloodlust. This monarch used camels to win the Battle of Thymbra, defeating Croesus of Lydia. His capture of Babylon is detailed in his namesake Cylinder, and Isaiah refers to him as a messiah for his freeing the Jews from the Babylonian Captivity. The satrapy system was created by, for ten points, what first Achaemenid ruler of the Persian empire?", "answer": "<b> Cyrus the Great</b> or<b> Cyrus II</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This university hosted the 1942 Rose Bowl after large outdoor gatherings during wartime were banned on the west coast. It won one national championship when Gordon Hayward\u2019s half court shot barely missed. The \u201cair ball\u201d taunt was popularized by fans of this university\u2019s basketball team, who camp outside Cameron Indoor Stadium in a tent complex named for its head coach, the current USA National Team coach. For ten points, name this university in Durham, North Carolina, which has won five men\u2019s basketball titles under Mike Krzyzewski [sha-SHEF-ski].", "answer": "<b> Duke</b> University", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "Oscar Niemeyer planned a new capital city for this country in 1956, to replace a southern city on Guanabara Bay that will host the 2016 Summer Olympics. For ten points, name this South American country, whose city of S\u02dcao Paulo is the largest in the Americas and whose capital was once Rio de Janeiro.", "answer": "<b> Brazil</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man succeeded Nathaniel Lyon as the Commander of the Department of the West during the Civil War. Fighting during the Mexican-American War was ended in one (+) territory after this man signed the Treaty of Cahuenga. His refusal to step down as the military governor of California led to being court martialed by (*)</b> Stephen Kearney. He finished second in the 1856 Presidential election to James Buchanan. For ten points, name this explorer who was the first Republican presidential nominee.", "answer": "John C.<b> Fremont</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This event ended the Peace of Saint-Germain-en-Laye. Pope Gregory XIII sent a Golden Rose to Charles IX in commemoration of this event, which saw Charles Danowitz kill</b> <b>Admiral (+)</b> <b>Gaspard de Coligny. It took place in the aftermath of the marriage between</b> <b>Gaspard de Coligny. It took place in the aftermath of the marriage between</b> <b>Margaret of Valois and (*)</b> <b>Margaret of Valois and (*)</b> Henry III of Navarre and was instigated by either Henry of Guise or Catherine de Medici. For ten points, name this 1572 massacre of Huguenots.", "answer": "<b> St. Bartholowmew\u2019s Day Massacre</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The Dog Tax War was begun by members of this ethnic group. Europeans allying with these people were known as \u201cPakeha.\u201d Te Kooti founded a form of Christianity that likened the (+) plight of these people to that of the Israelites; that religion is Ringatu. This group suffered great losses as a result of the (*)</b> Musket Wars. For ten points, name these people believed to have arrived in New Zealand from Polynesia in the 13th century.", "answer": "<b> Maori</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Upon this man\u2019s release from Pendennis Castle, he was gifted supplies in Cork, though he would not be free until was exchanged for the prisoner Archibald Campbell. He was captured</b> <b>by (+)</b> <b>Guy Carleton at the Battle of Longue-Pointe. William Delaplace surrendered to</b> <b>Guy Carleton at the Battle of Longue-Pointe. William Delaplace surrendered to</b> <b>this man before he captured (*)</b> <b>this man before he captured (*)</b> Saint-Jean and Crown Point, and he led a force founded at the Catamount Tavern. Benedict Arnold captured Fort Ticonderoga with, for ten points, what patriot who led the Green Mountain Boys in Vermont?", "answer": "Ethan<b> Allen</b> Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man broke up the Canal Ring as Governor of New York. The Senate appointment</b> <b>of Illinois\u2019 David Davis led to this man (+)</b> <b>losing an election when, after voting along</b> <b>party lines, a 15-member commission decided not to award this man any of the disputed (*) </b>electoral college votes. For ten points, name this winner of the popular vote for the Presidency in 1876 who ultimately lost the election to Rutherford B. Hayes.", "answer": "Samuel J.<b> Tilden</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Executives for this country\u2019s flag-carrying airline were attacked after announcing nearly 3,000 job cuts. In June, its CNIL threatened Google with fines if they did not apply the right to be forgotten to their global searches. During this country\u2019s elections for the (+) European Parliament, the right-wing National Front seized 25% of the vote, while its domestic government is led by (*)</b> Socialist Prime Minister Manuel Valls. For ten points, name this European country whose President, also a Socialist, is Francois Hollande.", "answer": "<b> France</b> ", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>Right before the end of this conflict, action in the Battle of 73 Easting continued</b> <b>at Norfolk, and Frederick Franks lost almost no troops while demolishing the (+)</b> <b>Republican Guard in this war. It began over disputes about the Rumaila oil field.</b> <b>Chuck Horner commanded troops in this war before the arrival of (*) </b> Norman Schwarzkopf. For ten points, name this war in which Operation Desert Storm reacted to Saddam Hussein\u2019s invasion of Kuwait.", "answer": "Persian<b> Gulf War</b> (or First<b> Gulf War</b>,<b> First Iraq War</b>; prompt on Operation <b>Desert Storm</b> until mention)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}